[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Who proposed the Preamble before the Drafting Committee of the Constitution.",
    "option1": "Jawaharlal Nehru",
    "option2": "B.R. Ambedkar",
    "option3": "B.N.Rau",
    "option4": "Mahatma Gandhi",
    "correctans": "Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Who is the guardian of fundamental Rights enumerated in Indian Constitution.?",
    "option1": "Supreme Court",
    "option2": "Parliament",
    "option3": "Constitution",
    "option4": " President",
    "correctans": "Supreme Court"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "The first Law Officer of the Government of India is the ",
    "option1": "Union Law Minister",
    "option2": "Secreatary, Ministry of Law",
    "option3": "Attorney-General for India",
    "option4": "Chief Justice of the Supreme Court",
    "correctans": "Attorney-General for India"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The Constitution of India borrowed the scheme of Indian Federation from the constitution of ",
    "option1": "USA",
    "option2": "Canada",
    "option3": "United Kingdom",
    "option4": "Ireland",
    "correctans": "Canada"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Who have the power to decide an election petition.?",
    "option1": "Parliament",
    "option2": "Supreme Court",
    "option3": "High Courts",
    "option4": "Election Commission",
    "correctans": "High Courts"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which of the following exercised the most profound influence in framing the Indian Constitution.?",
    "option1": "British Constitution",
    "option2": "US Constitution",
    "option3": "Irish Constitution",
    "option4": "The Government of India Act 1935",
    "correctans": "The Government of India Act,1935"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "The item ' Education' belongs to the ",
    "option1": "Union List",
    "option2": "State List",
    "option3": "Concurrent List",
    "option4": " Residuary",
    "correctans": "Concurrent List"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Who was the Chairman of the Union Power Committee of Constituent Assembly of India?",
    "option1": "Sardar",
    "option2": "Dr. B.R.Ambedkar",
    "option3": "Sir Allad",
    "option4": " Pt. Jawaharlal",
    "correctans": " Pt. Jawaharlal"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Who called Indian Federalism as the Co-operative Federalism",
    "option1": "G.Austin",
    "option2": "K.C.Wheare",
    "option3": "Sir Ivor Jennings",
    "option4": " D.D.Basu",
    "correctans": "G.Austin"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Article 1 of the Constitution declares India as",
    "option1": "Fedaral State",
    "option2": " Quasi Federal State",
    "option3": "Unitary State",
    "option4": "Union of States",
    "correctans": "Union of States"
  }
]
